<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>UCLCHEM Blog</title>
        <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>The best place to stay up-to-date with the latest UCLCHEM news and events.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <image>
            <title>UCLCHEM Blog</title>
            <url>https://uclchem.github.io/img/uclchem-logo.jpg</url>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2021 Jon Holdship</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First measurement of nitrogen fractionation in shocked clumps of the L1157 protostellar outflow. SOLIS XI]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2020/12/07/milena-nitrogen-solis.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2020/12/07/milena-nitrogen-solis.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>As part of the SOLIS observational programme, various isotopologues of HCN were observed towards L1157 in order to study the nitrogen fractionation in a protostellar outflow. The modelling work for this study was done using UCLCHEM. You can find <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2011.14882.pdf">the ...</a></p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Website]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2020/02/14/New-Website.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2020/02/14/New-Website.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We're replacing our old website! The old site was essentially just a poster for UCLCHEM with some github links. The new website has a similar landing page but importantly, we've moved all the documentation for UCLCHEM online. We'll keep that up to da...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A chemical study of carbon fractionation in external galaxies]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2019/08/13/serena-carbon-frac.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2019/08/13/serena-carbon-frac.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>UCLCHEM has recently been used to study carbon fractionation in external galaxies. You can find <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.12405.pdf">the paper here</a> and the abstract below.</p> <p>In the interstellar medium carbon exists in the form of two stable isotopes 12C and 13C and their ratio is a good i...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambipolar diffusion and the molecular abundances inprestellar cores]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2019/07/08/felix-ambipolar.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2019/07/08/felix-ambipolar.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://fpriestley.github.io/">Felix Priestley</a> has used UCLCHEM in an investigation of the chemical differences caused by the magnetic fields in prestellar cores. You can find <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1907.02736.pdf">the paper here</a> and the abstract below.</p> <p>We investigate differences in the molecular abundances between mag...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitrogen fractionation in external galaxies]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2019/04/19/serena-nitrogen-frac.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2019/04/19/serena-nitrogen-frac.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>UCLCHEM has recently been used to study nitrogen fractionation in external galaxies. You can find <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1904.11725.pdf">the paper here</a> and the abstract below.</p> <p>In star-forming regions in our own Galaxy, the 14N/15N ratio is found to vary from ∼100 in meteorites, comets, an...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Collapsing Prestellar Cores - a new physics module]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/07/12/felix-collapse.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/07/12/felix-collapse.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://fpriestley.github.io/">Felix Priestley</a> has used UCLCHEM to study the collapse of prestellar cores. In the process, he's created a new physics module <code>collapse.f90</code> which follows a sphere of gas collapsing in different ways. The <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1806.01699.pdf">paper can be found here</a> and the abstract is bel...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Chemistry of Phosphorus-bearing Molecules under Energetic Phenomena]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/06/20/izaskun-phosphorus.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/06/20/izaskun-phosphorus.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Izaskun Jimenez-Serra has published a study of the chemistry of phosophorus bearing species using UCLCHEM. The <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1806.07281.pdf">paper can be found here</a> and the abstract is below.</p> <p>For decades, the detection of phosphorus-bearing molecules in the interstellar medium wa...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chemical modelling of glycolaldehyde and ethylene glycol in star-forming regions]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/03/27/audrey-coms.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/03/27/audrey-coms.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Audrey Coutens has published modelling work on glycoaldehyde and ethylene glycol using UCLCHEM. You can find <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.08778">the paper here</a> and the abstract below.</p> <p>Peptide bonds (N-C = O) play a key role in metabolic processes since they link amino acids into peptid...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chemical modelling of complex organic molecules with peptide-like bonds in star-forming regions]]></title>
            <link>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/02/05/david-grains.html</link>
            <guid>https://uclchem.github.io/blog/2018/02/05/david-grains.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>David Quenard just published an update to the UCLCHEM with an application to COMs in prestellar cores <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1711.05184">you can find the paper here</a> and the abstract below.</p> <p>Peptide bonds (N-C = O) play a key role in metabolic processes since they link amino acids into ...</p>]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>